<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>route53 on Shining Moon</title>
    <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/route53/</link>
    <description>Recent content in route53 on Shining Moon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>monsterxx03</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:55:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/route53/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get all invalid PTR record on  Route53</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2017/09/29/get-all-invalid-ptr-record-on-route53/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 08:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2017/09/29/get-all-invalid-ptr-record-on-route53/</guid>
      <description>I use autoscaling group to manage stateless servers. Servers go up and down every day.
Once server is up, I will add a PTR record for it’s internal ip. But when it’s down, I didn’t cleanup the PTR record. As times fly, a lot of invalid PTR records left in Route53.
To cleanup those PTR records realtime, you can write a lambda function, use server termination event as trigger. But how to cleanup the old records at once?
Straightforward way is write a script to call AWS API to get a PTR list, get ip from record, test whether the ip is live, if not, delete it.
Since use awscli to delete a Route53 record is very troublesome (involve json format), you’d better write a python script to delete them. I just demo some ideas to collect those records via shell.
You can do it in a single line, but make things clear and easy to debug, I split it into several steps.
Get PTR record list aws route53 list-resource-record-sets --hosted-zone-id xxxxx --query &amp;quot;ResourceRecordSets[?Type==&#39;PTR&#39;].Name&amp;quot; | grep -Po &#39;&amp;quot;(.+?)&amp;quot;&#39; | tr -d \&amp;quot; &amp;gt; ptr.txt  ptr.txt will contain lines like:
1.0.0.10.in-addr.arpa. 2.0.0.10.in-addr.arpa.  Get ip list from PTR records cat ptr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>