<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fpm on Shining Moon</title>
    <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/fpm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fpm on Shining Moon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>monsterxx03</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 09:40:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/fpm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build deb repository with fpm , aptly and s3</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2017/06/23/build-deb-repository-with-fpm-aptly-and-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 09:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2017/06/23/build-deb-repository-with-fpm-aptly-and-s3/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;m lazy, I don&amp;#8217;t want to be deb/rpm expert, I don&amp;#8217;t want to maintain repo server. I want as less maintenance effort as possible. 🙂
Combine tools fpm, aptly with aws s3, we can do it.
Use fpm to convert python package to deb fpm can transform python/gem/npm/dir/&amp;#8230; to deb/rpm/solaris/&amp;#8230; packages
Example:
fpm -s python -t deb -m xyj.asmy@gmail.com --verbose -v 0.10.1 --python-pip /usr/local/pip Flask  It will transform Flask 0.10.1 package to deb. Output package will be python-flask_0.10.1_all.deb
Notes:
 If python packages rely on some c libs like MySQLdb (libmysqlclient-dev), you need to install them on the machine to build deb binary. By default fpm use easy_install to build packages, some packages like httplib2 have permission bug with easy_install, so I use pip By default, msgpack-python will be convert to python-msgpack-python, I don&amp;#8217;t like it, so add -n python-msgpack to normalize the package name. Some package&amp;#8217;s dependencies&amp;#8217; version number is not valid(eg: celery 3.1.25 deps pytz &amp;gt;= dev), so I replace the dependencies with --python-disable-dependency pytz -d &#39;pytz &amp;gt;= 2016.7&#39; fpm will not dowload package&amp;#8217;s dependency automatically, you need to do it by your self  Use aptly to setup deb repository aptly can help build a self host deb repository and publish it on s3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>