<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ALB on Shining Moon</title>
    <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/alb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ALB on Shining Moon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>monsterxx03</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 15:20:37 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/alb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Real Client Ip on AWS</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/02/01/get-real-client-ip-on-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 15:20:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/02/01/get-real-client-ip-on-aws/</guid>
      <description>If you run a webserver on AWS, get real client ip will be tricky if you didn&#39;t configure server right and write code correctly.
Things related to client real ip:
 CloudFront (cdn) ALB (loadbalancer) nginx (on ec2) webserver (maybe a python flask application).  Request sequence diagram will be like following:
User&#39;s real client ip is forwarded by front proxies one by one in head X-Forwarded-For.
For CloudFront:
 If user&#39;s req header don&#39;t have X-Forwarded-For, it will set user&#39;s ip(from tcp connection) in X-Forwarded-For If user&#39;s req already have X-Forwarded-For, it will append user&#39;s ip(from tcp connection) to the end of X-Forwarded-For  For ALB, rule is same as CloudFront, so the X-Forwarded-For header pass to nginx will be the value received from CloudFront + CloudFront&#39;s ip.
For nginx, things will be tricky depends on your config.
Things maybe involved in nginx:
 real ip module proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for;  If you didn&#39;t use real ip module, you need to pass X-Forwarded-For head explictly.
proxy_set_header X-Forwarded-For $proxy_add_x_forwarded_for; will append ALB&#39;s ip to the end of X-Forwarded-For header received from ALB.
So X-Forwarded-For header your webserver received will be user ip,cloudfront ip, alb ip
Or you can use real ip module to trust the value passed from ALB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>