<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code-infra on Shining Moon</title>
    <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/code-infra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code-infra on Shining Moon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <copyright>monsterxx03</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 13:58:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.monsterxx03.com/tags/code-infra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>用 Bloom filter 给推荐列表去重</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/11/17/%E7%94%A8-bloom-filter-%E7%BB%99%E6%8E%A8%E8%8D%90%E5%88%97%E8%A1%A8%E5%8E%BB%E9%87%8D/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 13:58:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/11/17/%E7%94%A8-bloom-filter-%E7%BB%99%E6%8E%A8%E8%8D%90%E5%88%97%E8%A1%A8%E5%8E%BB%E9%87%8D/</guid>
      <description>之前产品里有一个功能是每天给用户推荐一批文章,要保证最后推给用户的文章每天不重复. 原先的实现很直接, 每次推送时候记录下用户 id 和 topic id 的键值对, 拿到新 topic 列表后,取出曾经给该用户推送过的文章列表, 两个 set 去重. 这个实现的问题很明显, 存储空间量太大(M * N), user id (int64) + topic id (int64) = 16 bytes, 1 million 的用户, 每天给用户推送10篇文章, 一年要存储: 16 * 10 * 365 * 1M = 54.4GB. 查询效率也很低,要么一次取所有已读 topic id, 要么把要推送的 topic id 都丢进数据</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>升级celery 到 4.2.0 碰到的坑</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/06/22/%E5%8D%87%E7%BA%A7celery-%E5%88%B0-4.2.0-%E7%A2%B0%E5%88%B0%E7%9A%84%E5%9D%91/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 16:10:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/06/22/%E5%8D%87%E7%BA%A7celery-%E5%88%B0-4.2.0-%E7%A2%B0%E5%88%B0%E7%9A%84%E5%9D%91/</guid>
      <description>在把代码往 python3 迁移的过程中需要升级一些第三方库, 升级了 gevent 后发现 celery 有问题, 于是尝试把 celery 从3.1.25 升级到 4.2.0, 中间碰到了很多问题, 记录一点. 配置的变化 CELERY_ACCEPT_CONENT 之前默认是都允许的, 4.0 开始默认值只允许 json, 因为我用的是msgpack, 所以需要修改这个配置让它接受 msgpack. CELERY_RESULT_SERIALIZER 之前默认是pickle, 现在默认也变成了json, 如果task 的返回结果是 binary 的话, json 无法处理,要么把结果 base64 编码, 要么把CELERY_RESULT_SERI</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SNS &amp; SQS to build Pub/Sub System</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/05/23/use-sns-sqs-to-build-pub/sub-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 18:05:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/05/23/use-sns-sqs-to-build-pub/sub-system/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we build pub/sub system based on AWS&#39;s SNS &amp;amp; SQS service, take some notes.
Originally, we have an pub/sub system based on redis(use BLPOP to listen to a redis list). It&#39;s really simple, and mainly for cross app operations. Now we have needs to enhance it to support more complex pubsub logic, eg: topic based distribution. It don&#39;t support redelivery as well, if subscribers failed to process the message, message will be dropped.
There&#39;re three obvious choices in my mind:
 kafka AMQP based system (rabbitmq,activemq &amp;hellip;) SNS + SQS  My demands for this system are:
 Support message persistence. Support topic based message distribution. Easy to manage.  The data volume won&#39;t be very large, so performance and throughput won&#39;t be critical concerns.
I choose SNS + SQS, main concerns are from operation side:
 kafka need zookeeper to support cluster. rabbitmq need extra configuration for HA, and AMQP model is relatively complex for programming.  So my decision is:
 application publish message to SNS topic Setup multi SQS queues to subscribe SNS topic Let different application processes to subscribe to different queues to finish its logic.  SQS and SNS is very simple, not too much to say, just some notes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Sqlalchemy</title>
      <link>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/05/20/migrate-to-sqlalchemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 15:11:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.monsterxx03.com/2018/05/20/migrate-to-sqlalchemy/</guid>
      <description>最近把公司 db 层的封装代码基于 sqlalchemy 重写了, 记录一些. 原来的 db 层代码历史非常古老(10年以上&amp;hellip;), 最早写代码的人早就不在了, 问题很多: 完全没有单元测试. 暴露出的接口命名很混乱, 多数是为了兼容一些历史问题. 里面带一套 client 端 db sharding 的逻辑, 但在新项目里完全用不到, 还导致无法做 join, 无法子查询, 很不方便. 老的 db 代码没有 model 层, 和 db migration 通过一种很 trick 的方式绑定在一起实现的, 导致开发时候对着代码完全无法知道数据库表</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>